citibank.co.in 2019-05-20

# Citibank

**For Resident Indians and NRIs - Privacy for Consumers at Citi**

Our goal is to maintain your trust and confidence while handling personal information about you.

**You have Choices**

As a Citi customer, you have the opportunity to make choices about how personal information about you may be shared. As you consider this, we encourage you to make choices that enable us to provide you with quality products and services, that help you meet your financial needs and objectives.

**Security of Personal Information**

The security of personal information about you is our priority. We protect this information by maintaining physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that meet applicable law. We train our employees in the proper handling of personal information. When we use other companies to provide services for us, we require them to protect the confidentiality of personal information they receive.

**Citi Online Privacy Statement**

Our Online Privacy Statement does not cover information you provide to the websites we advertise on and may link to. We encourage you to read the privacy policies on these sites.

Our Online Privacy Statement describes below how we may collect, use and share information you provide when you visit this website, receive our emails or interact with advertisements we have on third-party websites.

Click on    to expand and on    to minimize the details.

We collect two types of online information: Non-Personal and Personal.

**Non-Personal Information**

When you visit our site, we collect the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet. In addition, we gather information such as what browser and which version of it you're using, the type of operating system you have, and which site you came from. This information helps us provide an online experience that matches your device. 

When you browse our site or receive one of our emails, Citi and companies we work with, use cookies and/or pixel tags to collect information and store your online preferences. Cookies are widely used and most browsers are set up to accept them automatically. If you would prefer, you can choose to not accept cookies.

It's important to note that cookies and pixel tags do not capture any information that can personally identify you. The information they gather helps us improve your online experience and may include: 

  * Your response to one of our emails
  * Time and duration of your visit to our site
  * Pages you viewed while on our site

We may also supplement the information we collect with information we receive from other companies. For example, we may use marketing segments developed by us or other companies to customize certain services to your local area and provide relevant Citi offers tailored to you.

**Personal Information**

In addition to the information described in the previous section, we may also gather personal information that you provide to us such as your name, address, phone number, and email. Collecting this personal information enables us to offer you online experiences that help you with your financial needs. For example, we collect personal information when you are: 

  * Banking online
  * Applying for a new program or account

If you've enrolled in Citi services, such as online bill payment, we collect personal information about your transactions, and how you interact with third parties such as those you pay like a utility company or phone company. Collecting this information enables us to provide you these services. You can refer to the Terms and conditions for your account or service to learn how your information is collected and used.

If we have personal information from you, or information that's publicly available from other sources, we may use it in combination with the information that Citi has collected online. We can use this information to better tailor and personalize our service and marketing communications with you, both online and offline.

The personal information you provide online is held by the Citi business that maintains your account or is processing your application for a new product or service. You can access and/or change information in connection with your account or application by logging on to your account online or telephoning customer service.

Citi uses the information we collect about and from you to manage our business and to offer an enhanced, personalized online experience on our site and third-party websites.

The information we collect allows us to:

  * Recognize you when you return to our site so we can personalize your experience
  * Process applications and transactions
  * Respond to your requests
  * Provide you relevant product and service offers on our site and in other advertising

Companies we work with place and track advertisements on third-party websites.

Like most advertisers, we place advertisements where we think they will be most relevant to customers. We place advertisements by developing and using our own marketing segments that may combine online and offline information about our current and prospective customers. In addition, we may use marketing segments provided by online publishers and network advertising companies.

Network advertising companies that provide these services have their own privacy policies and are not subject to our Online Privacy Statement. Many of these companies provide ways to avoid targeted advertising provided by, or thru, them.

It's important to note that the information we use about you helps us provide you with products, services and experiences that benefit you. You have the ability to control how your non-personal information is collected and used online. 

**Cookies**

You can control whether to accept cookies or not. If you decide to not accept cookies, some features and services on our site may not work properly because we may not be able to recognize and associate you with your Citi account(s). In addition, the offers we provide when you visit us may not be as relevant to you or tailored to your interests. 

If you would prefer not to accept cookies, you can: 

  * Change your browser settings to notify you when you receive a cookie, which lets you choose whether or not to accept it
  * Set your browser to automatically not accept any cookies

**Notice of changes**

From time to time, we may change this Online Privacy Policy. The effective date of this policy, as stated below, indicates the last time this policy was revised or materially changed. Checking the effective date below allows you to determine whether there have been changes since the last time you reviewed the policy. 

**Effective Date**

This policy was last modified in Sep, 2011.

citibank.com/india and citinri.com is managed by Citibank India and enable online access to account information and transaction services for clients of Citibank India. In addition, citibank.com/india, citinri.com and asia.citi.com accepts applications for Citibank India. This disclosure does not address how information is handled by or the policy of any other affiliate or third party site that may be linked to these sites.

This comprehensive privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") provides the practices and policies of Citibank N.A. ("Citibank") for handling of or dealing in customer information ("Customer Information"), including Sensitive Personal Data of the Customer (as defined below) that has been lawfully collected by Citibank from its customers ("Customers"). It also provides the type of Sensitive Personal Data collected by Citibank, the purpose of collection and usage of such data, their disclosure norms and the reasonable security practices and procedures adopted by Citibank in this regard. This Privacy Policy is applicable to all Customer Information collected by Citibank. Citibank reserves the right to amend its prevailing Privacy Policy from time to time at its sole discretion and shall place any such amendments on this website.

Click on    to expand and on    to minimize the details.

  * Citibank receives Customer Information from various sources, including Customer application forms, online surveys, contests, promotions, transaction with affiliate or non-affiliated third parties, credit bureaus, employers, etc. Such Customer Information, includes but may not be limited to name, address, date of birth, identification number, telephone number, e-mail, occupation, assets and income, account balances, payment history, account activity, credit worthiness, etc.
  * The Customer Information received by Citibank may relate to personal data or information of the Customers consisting of passwords, financial information such as bank account or Credit Card or Debit Card or other payment instrument details, physical, physiological and mental health condition, sexual orientation, medical records and history, biometric information and any other detail relating to the above. The Customer Information specified in this paragraph 2 is hereinafter referred to as "Sensitive Personal Data". However, any such information that is freely available or accessible in public domain or furnished under the Right to Information Act, 2005 or any other law for the time being in force shall not be regarded as Sensitive Personal Data

  * Citibank may collect, store, use, transfer or disclose Customer Information, including Sensitive Personal Data, for any or all of the following purposes: 
    * For provision, operation, processing or administration of any services provided to Customers, including responding to Customer requests
    * For data processing, statistical or risk analysis
    * For conducting credit or anti-money laundering cheques and collection of debit and assisting other financial institutions in relation thereto
    * For purposes of credit reporting, verification and risk management, we will exchange Customer Information with reputable reference sources and clearing house services
    * For determining the amount of indebtedness owed by Customers or to them and to ensure ongoing credit worthiness of Customers
    * For designing and marketing financial services or related products or opportunities from Citibank and its affiliates and providing the same to the Customers
    * To meet the disclosure requirements of any law binding on Citibank
    * To enable an actual or proposed assignee of Citibank or transferee of Citibank's rights to evaluate the transaction intended to be the subject of the assignment or transfer
    * To manage our business and to offer an enhanced, personalized online experience on our website and third-party websites
    * For all other incidental and associated purposes relating to the provision of services
  * Our affiliates are the family of companies controlled by Citigroup Inc. We may share Customer Information with affiliates in several different lines of business, including banking, credit cards, consumer finance, securities and insurance
  * Non-affiliated third parties are those not part of the family of companies controlled by Citigroup Inc. We may disclose Customer Information to the following types of   
non-affiliated third parties: 
    * Financial services providers such as companies engaged in banking, Credit Cards, consumer finance, securities and insurance
    * Non-financial organizations such as companies engaged in direct marketing and the selling of consumer products and services

  * Citibank will safeguard, according to applicable standards of security and confidentiality, any information that Customers share with us and will ensure Sensitive Personal Data is only used for the purpose specified at the time of collection
  * We will limit the collection and use of Customer Information to the minimum we require to deliver superior service to our Customers and for the purposes set out in Part II above
  * We will permit only authorized employees, who are trained in the proper handling of Customer Information, to have access to that Customer Information. Employees who violate our Privacy Policy will be subject to our disciplinary process
  * We will not reveal Customer Information to any external third party organization except, for the purposes mentioned in Part II above or for any other purposes and such disclosure, has been previously authorized by the Customer or is required by law or any regulatory or governmental body or agency or is required for the purpose of performing a lawful contract with the Customer or is required pursuant to a duty to the public or is necessary in the interest of Citibank
  * Whenever we hire other organizations to provide support services, we will require them to conform to our Privacy Policy and to allow us to audit them for compliance
  * We will attempt to keep Customer files complete, up to date and accurate. We will tell our Customers how and where to conveniently access their Customer Information and how to notify us about errors, which we will promptly correct. Existing Customer of Citibank having an online account with us, can access and/or change Customer Information in connection with their account by logging on to their account online or telephoning customer service
  * Customers will at all times have the option of not providing us with Sensitive Personal Data that we seek to collect. Even after the Customer has provided us with any Sensitive Personal Data, he / she will have the option to withdraw the consent given earlier. In such cases, Citibank will have the right to not provide or discontinue the provision of any service that is linked with such Sensitive Personal Data

  * We protect Customer Information from unauthorized access and use by maintaining physical, electronic and procedural safeguards. Citibank uses and has a comprehensive documented information security program and information security policies that contain managerial, technical, operational and physical security control measures that are commensurate with the Customer Information being protected1
  * Third parties who may have access to Customer Information must agree to follow appropriate standards of security and confidentiality
  * Sensitive Personal Data is retained by Citibank for as long as the purpose for which such Sensitive Personal Data were collected exist. Thereafter, such Sensitive Personal Data is destroyed, unless retention thereof is required to satisfy legal, regulatory or accounting requirements

If a Customer does not wish to receive any marketing material / information from us, they can contact us to remove their name from our list.

Customers can contact us by writing to us at the mailing address given below:

Citibank N.A., Mail Room,  
ACROPOLIS, 9th Floor,  
New Door No.148 (Old No.68),  
Dr. Radhakrishnan Salai, Mylapore,  
Chennai – 600 004.

Request for access to Sensitive Personal Data or correction of Sensitive Personal Data or for information regarding policies and practices and kinds of data held should be addressed to: Mr. M. Dhananjayan on [principal.nodal.officer@citi.com](mailto:principal.nodal.officer@citi.com "principal.nodal.officer@citi.com")
